Anneta Wamono

Kitchener, Ontario P: https://annetawamono.github.io/portfolio/ E: annetawamono@yahoo.com.au

Frontend Developer

An enthusiastic and dedicated freelance Web Developer and Designer with four years of experience developing websites for small businesses. Highly organised with the ability to work independently of my own initiative while also being a part of a successful team, demonstrating the motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining the highest standards. I am currently looking for a new and challenging position as a Frontend Developer where I can develop product-building experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Studio Locale, Kitchener, ON

May 2022

Studio Locale is a marketing, design and development studio working with companies of all scales.

- I developed updated designs for four existing websites for a multi-provincial student residential management company. My contributions included improving accessibility, meeting AODA compliance, and increasing core web vitals to 80+ scores.
- I have migrated several client sites from UA to GA4 and set up conversions for crucial site metrics.

Web Developer Volunteer

Link Up Festival, Waterloo, ON

Jun 2020 - Jul 2021

Link Up is a yearly festival celebrating Waterloo's African Caribbean cultural diaspora.

- I brought my WordPress experience to a team of new web developer volunteers. I helped them upskill their website design, UX and development skills.
- I developed a plugin for their marketplace that allows festival vendors' information to be managed and displayed.

Freelancer

Cape Town, South Africa

Aug 2019 - Current

As a freelance web developer and designer, I often take my clients from design to production on their websites. My client's businesses cater to niche markets.

- I designed and developed an e-commerce store for a client where they could sell physical goods, digital goods and tickets to events.
- I improved the page performance of an inherited site by 50% to help improve my client's SEO ranking.
- I wrote articles and used targeted keywords to help improve the SEO ranking for my clients.

Design/Developer Intern

Karbon Black, Pretoria

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

Karbon Black is a digital design studio that provides branding, UI/UX and development services.

- I worked closely with a client to develop an MVP for his product that secured investments.
- I trained with the Lead Designer and took on UX work in the company.

University Tutor

University of Pretoria

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Anneta Wamono Page 2

The University of Pretoria is a tertiary education institution.

- I was a tutor for Intro to Computer Science and Operating Systems modules.
- I assisted lecturers with grading homework, organising schedules and designing tasks, and assisting students taking a degree course in Computer Science.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Design and Development, Conestoga College.

May 2020 - Aug 2022

<u>Modules included:</u> Responsive site design, Javascript programming, Web security, Database design, MEAN development, and Data visualisation.

• Instructors with many years of industry experience teach this program, and it gave me insight into best practices and leading technology.

Classical Animation, Vancouver Film School.

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

Main project: One traditionally animated short film and one digital short film.

• This program focuses on the 12 principles of animation, animated film production and visual arts.

BIS in Multimedia, University of Pretoria.

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

<u>Modules included:</u> Data structures and algorithms, Software modelling, and Concurrent systems. Main project: A functional game MVP designed and developed by a group.

• This degree combines computer science modules, visual design and human-computer interaction. It equipped me with the fundamentals of software development and an overview of UX/UI design.

Courses:

- Member of frontendmentors.io
- Participant in hacktoberfest 2021
- Completed Vue.js 2 Academy by Chris Dixon

Software skills:

- Git/Github
- VSCode
- Google Workplace
- Google Analytics 4

- Google Search Console
- Figma
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch
- Adobe After Effects, Premiere, Animate

CMS:

- WordPress
- Craft CMS
- Express Engine

Framework:

Nuxt